# SOFIA REIS

# PERSONAL INFORMATION

Born in Portugal, 7 August 1994

email sofia.o.reis@tecnico.ulisboa.pt

website https://sofiaoreis.github.io/

*phone* +351 919 760 820

social media 🕠 · 📵 · 🏏

### віо

PhD Student in Software Engineering and Security at Instituto Superior Técnico, University of Lisbon and researcher at INESC-ID. Studying automated techniques to detect security software vulnerabilities. I also perform research in software maintainability, software fault localization and slicing. Active member of the QUASAR research group (TQRG).

#### **EDUCATION**

2018-2022 Instituto Superior Técnico, University of Lisbon

PhD in Computer Science and Engineering GPA: 19.4/20 · Waiting for PhD proposal defense

Thesis: Understanding and Improving Security-oriented Static Analysis Techniques

Advisor: Prof. Rui Abreu

2016-2017 Leiden Institute of Advanced Computer Science

*ERASMUS+ PROGRAMME* 

GPA: 7.5/10 · Computer Science and Advanced Data Analytics

Data Mining, Social Network Analysis, Big Data and Evolutionary Algorithms

Ref: Prof. Rosaldo Rossetti · rossetti@fe.up.pt

Faculty of Engineering of the University of Porto

BSc+MSc (Integrated Master) GPA: 15/20 · *Informatics and Computing Engineering (A3ES accreditation)*Thesis: Assessing software vulnerabilities using Naturally Occurring Defects

Mark: 19/20 - top 5% of the best thesis in the class of 2017

Advisor: Prof. Rui Abreu

## WORK EXPERIENCE

2018–Present Junior Researcher, INESC-ID — Lisbon

**INESC-ID** 

Analysis of the entire corpus of documents published in the last 30 years in the Portuguese law search engine. Funded by the INCM under the ref. "353/2017 - Serviço de pesquisa em linha para o Diário da Republica eletrónico (DRE)"

Ref: José Borbinha · jlb@tecnico.ulisboa.pt

2017–2018 RPA Developer, KPMG PT — Porto

KPMG PT

Robotic Process Automation Developer. Responsible for designing and delivering automations in Automation Anywhere for VAT processing in the pharmaceutical sector. Ref: Lara Conceição and Daniel Pires Certified in Automation Anywhere. License: AAADVC-Fv5QqG1JlD

TEACHING ASSISTANT July 2019 **Future of Computing** Conference 1-day training on the Fundamentals of accelerated computing with CUDA Python. Certified by NVIDIA. Ref: Cristiana Dinea · cdinea@nvidia.com Winter Software Engineering - Post-Graduation 2019/20 University 3-month course to AskBlue and Deloitte employees (1.5 month each). Instituto Superior Técnico, University of Lisbon, TagusPark. Ref: António Rito Silva · rito.silva@tecnico.ulisboa.pt Spring 2019 Software Engineering - 3rd year course Full 6-month course. Instituto Superior Técnico, University of Lisbon, Alameda. Ref: Rui Abreu · rui@computer.org · 8.62 out of 9 Fall 2018 Foundations of Programming - 1st year course Full 6-month course. Instituto Superior Técnico, University of Lisbon, TagusPark. Ref: Alberto Abad · alberto.abad@tecnico.ulisboa.pt · 9 out of 9 **PUBLICATIONS** 2019 [1] Sofia Reis, Rui Abreu and Marcelo D'Amorim. 2019. Demystifying the Combination of Dynamic Slicing and Spectrum-based Fault Localization. International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI) · Conference Paper · Core: A\* 2018 [2] Sofia Reis. 2018. Leveraging Known Vulnerabilities to Modernize Static Analysis Tools. PhD OpenDays 2018. Lisbon, Portugal · Poster [3] Sofia Reis and Rui Abreu. 2017. A Database of Existing Vulnerabilities to 2017 **Enable Controlled Testing Studies**. International Journal of Secure Software Engineering (IJSSE) 8 (3): 1-23 · Journal Paper [4] Sofia Reis and Rui Abreu. 2017. SECBENCH: A Database of Real Security Vulnerabilities. Secure Software Engineering in DevOps and Agile Development (SecSE), co-located with ESORICS, Oslo, Noruega · Workshop Paper [5] Sofia Reis and Rui Abreu. 2017. Using Github to Create a Dataset of Natural Occurring Vulnerabilities. International Workshop on Principles of Diagnosis (DX), Bréscia, Italy · Abstract and Poster · Core: B GRANTS, HONORS AND AWARDS Excellence in Teaching the Foundations of Programming awarded by Instituto 2020 Superior Técnico, University of Lisbon - Diploma 2020 **IBM Quantum Challenge** Advanced Badge (196/1745). Finished last challenge

(req. score: 1600/my score: 147/winner score: 45)

for Continuous Inspection of Code Quality · 6 months

2019

2018

PhD Scholarship awarded by FCT, cf. SFRH/BD/143319/2019 · 4 years

Scholarship funded by FCT/MCTES through national funds (PIDDAC) under

the project UID/CEC/50021/2013 to perform a Systematic Survey on Platforms

# RELEVANT TRAINING

2020	Finding security vulnerabilities in Java with CodeQL Workshop (online at GitHub Satellite 2020)
2020	Finding security vulnerabilities in JavaScript with CodeQL Workshop (online at GitHub Satellite 2020)
2019	2-days Facebook Testing and Verification Symposium (FaceTAV), Facebook London, UK, November 2019 (invitation only)
2019	1-week Future of Computing Conference, Porto, PT, July 2019
2019	4-days VMCAI Summer School, Lisbon, PT, January 2019
2018	2-days Facebook Testing and Verification Symposium (FaceTAV), Facebook London, UK, November 2018 (invitation only)

# OTHER INFORMATION

Comm	unication
	Skills

2018 · Poster at PhD OpenDays 2018, Lisbon, PT

2017 · Poster at the International Workshop on Principles of Diagnosis (DX), Bréscia, IT

Volunteer

2019 · Future of Computing Conference (Porto, PT) · 1-week

2019 · ACM SIGPLAN Symposium on Principles of Programming Languages (POPL'19), Lisbon, PT · 1-week

2018  $\cdot$  International Conference on Software Quality, Reliability and Security (QRS'18), Lisbon, PT  $\cdot$  3-days

2017 · Talk a Bit (Porto, PT) — organized by FEUP · 1-day

Committee

2020 · CommitPorto (Porto, PT) — organized by AlumniEI-FEUP · 9-month

2019 · ICST2020 (Porto, PT): Sponsorship and social media · 1-year

2019 · CommitPorto (Porto, PT) — organized by AlumniEI-FEUP · 9-month

2018 · CommitPorto (Porto, PT) — organized by AlumniEI-FEUP · 9-month

Organization

2019 · Vice-President of AlumniEI-FEUP · 2-years

Languages

Portuguese · Mothertongue

English · Intermediate (fluent)

French · Basic · Basic

June 16, 2020